<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>Holger's Blog &#187; Maemo</title>
  <link href="http://blog.homac.de/atom-maemo.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.homac.de"/>
  <updated>2014-06-30T09:07:49+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.homac.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Holger Macht</name>
    <email>holger@homac.de</email>
  </author>

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  
  <entry>
    <title>Declaring MMPC unsupported, nearly deathlike</title>
    <link href="http://blog.homac.de"/>
    <updated>2011-10-08T20:02:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.homac.de/2011/10/08/declaring-mmpc-unsupported-nearly-deathlike</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.homac.de//2011/10/08/declaring-mmpc-unsupported-nearly-deathlike.html&quot;&gt;Declaring MMPC unsupported, nearly deathlike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Quite surprised by receiving yet another feature request about the
&lt;i&gt;Maemo Music Player Client&lt;/i&gt; for the Maemo platform. I always got some
mails here and then, but didn't receive one in quite a while. But just
that everybody knows:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;I hereby declare&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org&quot;&gt;MMPC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;officially unsupported, not to say dead, stone-dead in particular.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Nevertheless, it's nice to hear that the project still has (at least a
few) users, so that I can say it has been a success after all.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  
  <entry>
    <title>Maemo Music Player Client (MMPC) for Diablo</title>
    <link href="http://blog.homac.de"/>
    <updated>2009-02-24T08:56:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.homac.de/2009/02/24/maemo-music-player-client-mmpc-for-diablo</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.homac.de//2009/02/24/maemo-music-player-client-mmpc-for-diablo.html&quot;&gt;Maemo Music Player Client (MMPC) for Diablo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;




&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;  var disqus_url = &quot;http://blog.homac.de/?p=81&quot;; &lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Finally I took the time to respond to multiple requests about providing
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org&quot;&gt;mmpc 0.2.1&lt;/a&gt; packages for Diablo. That also gave me the possibility to try
the &lt;a href=&quot;https://garage.maemo.org/extras-assistant/index.php&quot;&gt;maemo autobuilder&lt;/a&gt; to upload my packages to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.maemo.org/Uploading_to_Extras&quot;&gt;extras repository&lt;/a&gt;. And well, it worked out. It's especially useful for those
people not running debian based systems, because with autobuilder you
don't have to care about signing and uploading the packages with debian
tools like debsign and dput.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, this is not a new release, these are just new packages build for the
Diable 4.1 distribution. I still did not manage to find the time to
enhance mmpc further. There are just too many other things like work and
university I have to care about. Either download the packages from &lt;a href=&quot;https://garage.maemo.org/frs/?group_id=193&quot;&gt; Maemo Garage&lt;/a&gt;, or just get it through the extras repository as usual.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  
  <entry>
    <title>Maemo Music Player Client 0.2.1</title>
    <link href="http://blog.homac.de"/>
    <updated>2008-04-14T15:21:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.homac.de/2008/04/14/maemo-music-player-client-</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.homac.de//2008/04/14/maemo-music-player-client-.html&quot;&gt;Maemo Music Player Client 0.2.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
I finally managed to get to work on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org&quot;&gt;MMPC&lt;/a&gt; after quite some time. MMPC 0.1
was 2007-11-14 08:45 (wow, that was pretty early in morning :-))
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org/images/mmpc.png&quot;  alt=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org/images/mmpc.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Well, mmpc-0.2.1 is available for immediate consumption. Changes, which
were major concerns until now, are:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New buttons and images, finally. And a new logo you can see above.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add tap-and-hold functionality to more places. For example, it's now
    possible to update the database from within the client.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add scroll windows to all preference tabs to display the full
    content.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bold the currently played track.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase connection timeout to 3 seconds. This will hopefully solve
    the strange disconnect issues I wasn't able to reproduce.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed tree browsing in playlist browser.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Fresh screenshots can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Packages are available from the
extras repository. So most people will get the update automatically (if
anything goes wrong, try to enable red pill mode). Otherwise, grab them
from &lt;a href=&quot;https://garage.maemo.org/frs/?group_id=193&quot;&gt;garage&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Next things will include the support for some plugins. Please report any
problems. Happy listening!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  

  

  

  

  

  

  
  <entry>
    <title>Fixing a broken N810, or... A new way to freeze a device</title>
    <link href="http://blog.homac.de"/>
    <updated>2008-01-12T14:05:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.homac.de/2008/01/12/fixing-a-broken-n-or-a-new-way-to-freeze-a-device</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.homac.de//2008/01/12/fixing-a-broken-n-or-a-new-way-to-freeze-a-device.html&quot;&gt;Fixing a broken N810, or&amp;hellip; A new way to freeze a device&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;




&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;  var disqus_url = &quot;http://blog.homac.de/?p=58&quot;; &lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Finally I ordered a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nokia.com/N810&quot;&gt;Nokia N810&lt;/a&gt; with my discount code provided by the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maemo.org&quot;&gt;Maemo&lt;/a&gt; project on Tuesday. It arrived Thursday. With all my tenseness and
pleasant anticipation, it looked and felt great while having a quick
glance. But the disenchantment followed right away:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Huh? What's that? It doesn't power on after shutting it down the first
time. Putting in the charger doesn't help. Removing the battery and
putting it back doesn't help. &quot;Charging&quot; it several hours (without any
sign that it does so) doesn't help. Removing the battery for several
minutes doesn't help. Checking with a original Nokia battery and charger
from a colleague doesn't help. What to do? (Already really frightened of
having received a broken device&amp;hellip;)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In the evening, I decided to remove the battery and put it on the
balcony. On the balcony? Why that? It only was a very vague
suspicion&amp;hellip;it's currently winter in Europe, you know
;-). Waiting&amp;hellip;(and maybe praying) about another 30 minutes. Device was
cold now. Inserting the battery, pushing the power button, and voila!
The N810 turns on and powers up properly. Happy about thinking that this
was only a temporary failure, I tried again some minutes later and the
device kept silent again. What a mess! Next day, another colleague came
to me telling me that he has exactly the same problem. And I already had
a temporary solution for him&amp;hellip;(Skip the next paragraph if you want to
read it immediately)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yahoo.com&quot;&gt;Yahoo&lt;/a&gt;'ing around, I found out that this is a well known problem, at
least for the customers, I don't know how it behaves to the Nokia
company/manufacturers. There are plenty of reports for this issue. On
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.internettablettalk.com/&quot;&gt;Internettablettalk&lt;/a&gt; and even in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.maemo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=2673&quot;&gt; Maemo bugzilla&lt;/a&gt; known as &quot;N800 Power
up Drama&quot;. Interestingly, the problem seems to also be present on N800
devices. But only the new and recent ones. So it seems that some
electronic parts like capacitors installed in recent devices (N800 and
N810) are causing this issue. I tried everything people are suggesting,
waiting a specific period of time before switching it on again, making
sure that everything fits properly, enabling r&amp;amp;d mode, and so on. Please
don't tell me &quot;Just don't power off the device&quot;, because that's what I'm
generally doing, but that's no choice when you're on the road running
out of battery. And you sometimes need to power down the device for
development, too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The only thing that seems to help:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch the device off
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the battery
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put the device to a fridge (without the battery) for about 30
     minutes. If you are impatient like I am, put it into a deep-freezer
     for about 10 minutes to get it cold. Hint: Use a plastic bag to
     protect it from moisture, and more importantly, don't forget about
     it while doing something else ;-)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take it out and insert the battery
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn it back on, you'll see that it works
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
This procedure was already verified on two devices.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Strange, I currently know of five people having a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nokia.com/N810&quot;&gt;N810&lt;/a&gt;, with two of them
showing this issue. This is really bad percentage. I already fear that
this is like the issue I encountered with my N800 and the display issue
where the right side of the touchscreen became more and more
unresponsive. Also widely known. To that time, I returned the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nokia.com/N800&quot;&gt;N800&lt;/a&gt; back
to Nokia, and it lasted solid 6 weeks until I got a repaired device. I
do not want to repeat that! I do not want to develop inside a scratchbox
without the possibility to see the outcome on a live device. But the
most frustrating thing I encounter these days is that there is no
official statement from Nokia about this issue. There's still not even
one for the display issue with the N800. Please correct me if I'm wrong.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The only thing which keeps me alive ( ;-) ) and which prevents me from
returning the device immediately is the hope that it can be fixed via
software. I just hope that there will be a statement by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nokia.com&quot;&gt;Nokia&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maemo.org&quot;&gt;Maemo&lt;/a&gt; people telling me: &quot;Be patient, we're working on the issue with
high pressure and we think it can be fixed with a firmware update&quot;. If
it really is a hardware issue, I at least hope that the issue is handled
as &quot;we've sold broken devices, process returned ones with high
priority!&quot;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Getting away from the bad news, if there wouldn't be those, I would
really be amazed by this gadget! As long as it's on, I just have fun
with it. I'm just very frustrated.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  

  

  
  <entry>
    <title>MMPC for Chinook</title>
    <link href="http://blog.homac.de"/>
    <updated>2007-11-14T12:04:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.homac.de/2007/11/14/mmpc-for-chinook</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.homac.de//2007/11/14/mmpc-for-chinook.html&quot;&gt;MMPC for Chinook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;




&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;  var disqus_url = &quot;http://blog.homac.de/?p=55&quot;; &lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Even before the N810 is shipped, I'm able to to announce &lt;a href=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org&quot;&gt;MMPC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://garage.maemo.org/frs/?group_id=193&quot;&gt;packages&lt;/a&gt;
for the new Chinook 4.0 (OS2008) release. Untested in real production
environments, of course, but I see no reason why it shouldn't work
outside my ARM development environment.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Packages are &lt;a href=&quot;https://garage.maemo.org/frs/?group_id=193&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (including libmpd). Please report any issues you might
encounter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now I'm eagerly awaiting the availability of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nokia.de/n810&quot;&gt;N810&lt;/a&gt; in Germany to
finally get rid of my discount code. Thanks Nokia!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org/images/playing.png&quot;  alt=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org/images/playing.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org/images/playing_1.png&quot;  alt=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org/images/playing_1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On a related note: I'm still looking for designers creating some nice,
&quot;Play&quot;, &quot;Stop&quot;, &quot;Pause&quot;, &quot;Backward&quot; and &quot;Forward&quot; buttons. These are
just too ugly in the current state. Nobody willing to help out?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  

  

  
  <entry>
    <title>MMPC for the N770</title>
    <link href="http://blog.homac.de"/>
    <updated>2007-10-18T21:24:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.homac.de/2007/10/18/mmpc-for-the-n</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.homac.de//2007/10/18/mmpc-for-the-n.html&quot;&gt;MMPC for the N770&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;  var disqus_url = &quot;http://blog.homac.de/?p=54&quot;; &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I am proud to announce that there finally are &lt;a href=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org&quot;&gt;Maemo Music Player Client&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://garage.maemo.org/frs/?group_id=193&quot;&gt;packages&lt;/a&gt; built for the N770 (OS2006). It is thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://wap.ecw.de&quot;&gt;Christopher Klein&lt;/a&gt;,
who did the required code changes and the rebuild, that my inbox will be
delivered from requests about this apparently important missing piece.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  
  <entry>
    <title>Couch potato goodies</title>
    <link href="http://blog.homac.de"/>
    <updated>2007-02-19T17:12:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.homac.de/2007/02/19/couch-potato-goodies</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.homac.de//2007/02/19/couch-potato-goodies.html&quot;&gt;Couch potato goodies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;




&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;  var disqus_url = &quot;http://blog.homac.de/?p=48&quot;; &lt;/script&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-1-1&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sec-1-1&quot;&gt;Maemo Music Player Client&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-1-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
As briefly mentioned last time, I got a developer code for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nokia.com/n800&quot;&gt;Nokia n800&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks. I already had a n770, so without further ado, I decided to
purchase one. And that really kept me on the go the last couple of
weeks. At home, my computer is connected to my stereo system to play my
mp3s with passable good sound. So having a n800 with wlan, I thought
there has to be a possibility to use it as remote control. Looking for
something at the web, I shortly found the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.musicpd.org&quot;&gt;Music Player Daemon (mpd)&lt;/a&gt; to
be used as a service running on my home computer managing and playing my
mp3 collection. And very easy to install. Well, first duty was to find a
good client that works on the n800. Trying two web based clients and
noticing that they are ugly was not really satisfying. It was not hard
to build the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.musicpd.org/gmpc.shtml&quot;&gt;Gnome Music Player Client&lt;/a&gt; with some small modifications
inside my scratchbox environment for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maemo.org&quot;&gt;Maemo&lt;/a&gt; platform. Too bad for me,
the GUI is optimised for higher screen resolutions and for multi
windowed systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The default multimedia player which comes along with the n800 is quite
nice IMO, so an interface similar to this would be best. Well, noticing
that Nokia didn't open source its code although there's a request from
within the community is quite disappointing. I thought they wouldn't do
things by halves, but, well, other story&amp;hellip; Hopefully there's at least
no patent or the like for the GUI, otherwise I just hope they won't sue
me for reverse engineering it ;-)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Writing my first own gtk application was quite exhausting. The
documentation is so horrible bad :-( I just wonder why there aren't more
tutorials out there. For instance, about IMHO common problems like
setting bold font of a row in a GtkTreeView. Well, after getting into
it, it was, hm, well, O.k. ;-)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So here it is:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org&quot;&gt;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-1-2&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sec-1-2&quot;&gt;Maemo Music Player Client (mmpc)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-1-2&quot;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org/images/playing_1.png&quot;  alt=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org/images/playing_1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It is based on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sarine.nl/gmpc&quot;&gt;Gnome Music Player Client&lt;/a&gt;, but has undergone quite
much modification like hildonization, Maemo menus, the new player
interface, etc&amp;hellip; The GUI got especially designed to be used as a remote
control, meaning that it should be good to use without the stylus. All
in all, it is more a fork than a port. The first couple of days really
show the huge interest in an application like this. At the time of
writing this, there are already 281 downloads as you can see on the
Maemo garage &lt;a href=&quot;https://garage.maemo.org/frs/?group_id=193&quot;&gt; project page&lt;/a&gt;. It's a great toy ;-)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Actually I had another cool feature in mind. The device being used as a
remote control, and only as a remote control, you do not want other
people using or seeing any other things on the device while managing
music. So I actually wanted to force fullscreen mode until a correct
password gets entered. The code is already finished, but there's one
problem. The actual user can just turn off the device and reboot ;-) So
anyone having any idea how to prevent the user to reboot the device?
There's no possibility to lock the device in a way that one has to enter
a password everytime the device boots. Something like a PIN in cell
phones would be good. I can catch the hardware button event, of course,
but the system is turned off in any case. Different story&amp;hellip;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What I'm currently looking for is a graphic designer. I'm usually not
very good at that. So someone out there either doing web design or is
willing and able to design some nice play, stop, forward, backward,
etc. buttons? Any help would be appreciated. In any case, visit the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mmpc.garage.maemo.org&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt; for more information.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Greetings, Holger
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  
</feed>
